	ERSONAL FORMATION	Carlos Gómez Guijarro
		_
CL	CURRENT POSITION 2019/10–	Date of birth 26th Dec. 1990   Nationality Spanish
0014		CNRS postdoctoral researcher at UMR AIM (DAp) - CEA Paris-Saclay Laboratory of Cosmology and Galaxy Evolution (LCEG)
RF	SERCH PROFILE	

My scientific interest is to discover our cosmic origins by exploring the formation and evolution of the structures in our Universe. In my research I use both detailed and statistical studies of galaxy samples and multiwavelength datasets ranging from X-ray to radio, being PI and Co-I of numerous observing time proposals. I always envision my research with a local and an international scope, collaborating with both small teams and big international collaborations. I am very active in transmitting my results in international conferences and my knowledge by supervising students.

EDUCATION				
2015/10–2019/03	PhD in Astrophysics, Niels Bohr Institute, University of Copenhagen, Denmark			
20.07.0 20.0700	PhD degree awarded on May 15, 2019 - Advisor: Sune Toft			
	Thesis: Connecting the Extremes - High-redshift Starbursts as Progenitors of Massive Galaxies			
2013/09–2014/09	Master of Science in Astrophysics, Universidad Complutense Madrid, Spain			
	Awarded with a distinction in the course Galaxy Formation and Evolution			
2008/09–2013/09	Bachelor of Science in Physics and Astrophysics, Universidad Complutense Madrid, Spain			
	Long cycle degree of 5 years - Top 10% of the class - Awarded with 12 distinctions			
RESEARCH EXPERIENCE				
2015/10–2019/09	PhD Fellow at Cosmic Dawn Center, Niels Bohr Institute, University of Copenhagen, Denmark			
	Prior 2018/07 PhD Fellow at Dark Cosmology Centre, Niels Bohr Institute			
2017/04–06	Visit internship (3 months) with Dominik Riechers at Cornell University, USA			
2017/02	Research visit (1 week) with ALMA ARC Node at Onsala Space Observatory, Sweden			
2016/09	Research visit (1 week) with Alexander Karim at AlfA Bonn, Germany			
2013/02-2015/09	Research assistant with Jesús Gallego at UCM, Spain			
2015/07	Research visit (1 month) with Omaira González-Martín at IRyA, Mexico			
2014/07–09	Internship (3 months) with Omaira González-Martín at IAC, Spain			
2009/03–05	Trainee (3 months) with Miguel Ángel González-Barrio at UCM, Spain			
COLLABORATIONS				
International teams and projects				
2023–	ALMA-FPA development study (co-l)			
2022–	Public Release Imaging for Extragalactic Research (JWST), PRIMER (member)			
2022–	The Cosmic Evolution Early Release Science Survey (JWST), CEERS (member)			
2019–	GOODS-ALMA, 1.1mm galaxy survey (data manager)			
2018–	BUFFALO, a HST survey in the Frontier Fields (member)			
2015–	The Cosmic Evolution Survey, COSMOS (member)			
2015–	SHARDS, an ESO/Gran Telescopio Canarias large program in GOODS-N and the Frontier Fields (member)			
International collaborations				

CEA Saclay/LAM/ObAS/IAP (France), DAWN/DARK (Denmark), ESO/AlfA Bonn (Germany), NRAO/Cornell

University/Stanford University/NASA Ames (USA), IRyA (Mexico), CAB/IAC/UCM (Spain)

## PUBLICATION SUMMARY

(as of 18th August 2023)

- 8 first-author publications in peer-reviewed journals with 209 citations
- 54 publications in peer-reviewed journals with 1380 citations
- H-index: 22

# SCHOLARSHIPS AND AWARDS

2015/10-2019/03

PhD Fellowship, Niels Bohr Institute, University of Copenhagen, Denmark

2014/07–2014/09 2013–2014 Summer Grant at the IAC within the Program of Initiation to Astrophysical Research Collaboration Scholarship by the Ministry of Education of the Spanish Government

Awarded to talented students to collaborate with a university department

2008-2009

Scholarship for Outstanding Students by the Education Office of the Community of Madrid Awarded to students with the top grades at the Spanish University Access Test

## KEY PRACTICAL SKILLS

### Data reduction

- Processing of optical/near-IR imaging drizzled data (JWST, HST)
- Calibration and imaging of (sub)mm/radio interferometric data (ALMA, VLA)
- Processing of optical/near-IR spectroscopy (Keck/MOSFIRE, NOT/ALFOSC and FIES)
- Processing of X-ray imaging data (Chandra)

#### Data analysis

- Development of an aperture photometry code
- Development of an interferometric uv-plane stacking code
- Analysis of optical/near-IR and sub(mm)/radio imaging and spectra
- Source detection, photometry, and catalog build-up of optical/near-IR (SExtractor, aperture and model fitting photometry) and (sub)mm/radio (PyBDSF, photometry in image and uv-plane) data
- SED fitting of optical/near-IR (EAZY, FAST, LePhare) and far-IR/panchromatic (CIGALE) data
- Morphological fitting of optical/near-IR (GALFIT, Statmorph) and (sub)mm/radio (CASA, GILDAS) data

## Computing

- Programming: Python, R, C/C++, MATLAB Mathematics: Maple, Mathematica
- Operating systems: Linux, Mac, Windows Office automation: LaTeX, MS Office, Mac tools

#### Languages

- Spanish: Mother tongue
- English: Full working proficiency (C2)
- French: Limited working proficiency (B2)

## OBSERVING TIME ALLOCATION AND EXPERIENCE

## Proposal time allocation

## Optical/near-IR:

PI - ESO/KMOS 110.23UN (8h B grade): Instantaneous star formation rate to uncover the role of compact star formation

Co-I – ESO/KMOS 110.240K (21.3h B grade): Uncovering the role of optically dark galaxies in an overdensity at z = 3.5

Co-I – ESO/X-Shooter 109.22Y5 (56h A grade): Deep spectroscopy of bright red massive quiescent galaxies at z ~ 2.5 - 3

Co-I - ESO/KMOS 109.23CE (31h B grade): The gas content of sub-millimeter compact galaxies at cosmic noon

 $\hbox{Co-I-Keck/MOSFIRE S22A-046 (2nights): The emerge of the first quiescent galaxies-take 2}\\$ 

Co-I - Gemini/GMOS 21BCF05 (9.8h): Are submm compact main sequence galaxies actually faded starbursts?

Co-I – Keck/MOSFIRE S20B-031 (2nights): The emerge of the first quiescent galaxies

Co-I – Keck/MOSFIRE S20A-037 (1nights): Direct spectroscopic confirmation of z > 4 quiescent galaxies

Co-I - Keck/MOSFIRE S18B-040 (1nights): Direct spectroscopic confirmation of z > 4 quiescent galaxies

Co-I - HST GO 15117 (101orbits): BUFFALO

Co-I – Keck/MOSFIRE S17B-106 (1nights): Direct spectroscopic confirmation of z > 4 quiescent galaxies

#### (Sub)mm/radio:

PI - VLA 22B-243 (13.2h B grade): The true extent of the cold gas content in a red sequence progenitor

PI – NOEMA W21CO (8h B grade): Uncovering a unique population of gas giants at z = 1.2

 $\mbox{\bf PI}-\mbox{\bf NOEMA\,W19CV}$  (7.3h B grade): Peering into the pace of massive galaxy evolution

Co-I – VLA 23B-125 (29.3h A grade): A systematic CO(1-0) survey of z = 2.5-4 protocluster cores

Co-I – NOEMA S23CT (5.4h A grade): CII follow-up for a dusty star-forming galaxy at z=6.09

Co-I – NOEMA S23CY (12h A grade): Revealing the interstellar medium of two extremely massive galaxies at z > 7

Co-I - NOEMA W22DA (14h B grade): JWST and NOEMA unveil the nature of submm-compact galaxies

Co-I – VLA 22B-124 (67.1h B grade): A golden reference for ISM studies of distant normal galaxies: completion

Co-I – ALMA 2022.1.00884.S (8.7h A grade): Redshift scans for dusty star-forming galaxies at cosmic dawn

```
Co-I – VLA 21A-043 (11.5h C grade): Flares, breaks and warps in the outskirts of the HI and stellar disk of UGC11859
                          Co-I – VLA 20B-247 (24.2h C grade): Investigating possible non-gravitational ICM heating in a galaxy cluster at z = 2
                          Co-I - VLA 20A-485 (9h C grade): Flares, breaks and warps in the outskirts of the HI and stellar disk of UGC11859
                          Co-I - NOEMA 225-19 (22h B grade): Knocking on giant's door: A large-scale view of candidate z > 4 dusty galaxies
                          Co-I – ALMA 2018.1.01676.S (9.4h C grade): A total mass profile for a prototypical z ~ 4.6 massive star forming disk galaxy
                          Co-I – ALMA 2018.1.01225.S (19.4h C grade): What is the origin and subsequent evolution of starbursts at z ~ 2?
                          Co-I – ALMA 2016.1.01001.S (14.6h C grade): What is the origin and subsequent evolution of starbursts at z ~ 2?
                          Gran Telescopio Canarias 10.4m (OSIRIS, 1night); Keck 10m (MOSFIRE, 2half-nights); Nordic Optical
Visitor observations
                          Telescope 2.6m (ALFOSC and FIES, 8nights); Calar Alto Observatory 2.2m (CAFOS and FOCES, 3nights)
CONFERENCES AND
WORKSHOPS
Invited talks
                          Participation through personal invitation:
               2023/06
                          French Society of Astronomy Meeting 2023, Strasbourg, France
               2023/03
                          The growth of galaxies in the early universe VIII, Sexten, Italy
               2022/11
                          BOBAFET (transdisciplinary SFH workshop), LAM, Marseille, France
               2022/03
                          The growth of galaxies in the early universe VII, Sexten, Italy
               2021/11
                          Sino-French workshop: Simulations and observations of galaxies and protoclusters, Nanjing (Virtual), China
               2021/10
                          High-z dusty galaxies, LAM, Marseille, France
               2020/01
                          The growth of galaxies in the early universe VI, Sexten, Italy
               2018/03
                          Galaxy interactions and mergers across cosmic time, Sexten, Italy
               2017/11
                          The physics of quenching massive galaxies at high redshift, Leiden, The Netherlands
Contributed talks
                          Participation through abstract review:
                          EAS 2022 - The main sequence: going beyond the scaling relation, Valencia, Spain
               2022/06
                          EAS 2022 - The ISM of infrared galaxies from present to cosmic noon, Valencia, Spain
               2022/06
               2022/03
                          Cosmic nuggets: A feast of compact and massive galaxies across the universe, Sexten, Italy
               2020/03
                          IAU Symposium 359: Galaxy evolution and feedback across different environments, Bento Gonçalves, Brazil
               2018/09
                          Birth, life and fate of massive galaxies and their central beating heart, Favignana, Italy
               2018/08
                          IAU GA 2018 - Division J Meeting - Build-up of galaxy clusters, Vienna, Austria
               2018/07
                          Spanish Society of Astronomy Meeting 2018, Salamanca, Spain
               2014/09
                          Spanish Society of Astronomy Meeting 2014, Teruel, Spain
Team meeting talks
                          Participation through team membership:
               2023/05
                          CEERS Team Meeting 2023, Austin, USA
               2022/07
                          COSMOS Team Meeting 2022, Paris, France
               2019/11
                          ASPECS Team Meeting 2019, Schloss Ringberg, Germany
               2019/09
                          GOODS-ALMA Meeting 2019, CEA Saclay, France
               2018/06
                          COSMOS Team Meeting 2018, Copenhagen, Denmark
               2017/07
                          COSMOS Team Meeting 2017, Kyoto, Japan
               2016/06
                          COSMOS Team Meeting 2016, Baltimore, USA
Posters
                          Participation through abstract review:
                          EAS 2023 - Coming out of darkness: how JWST is changing our view of high-z dusty galaxies, Kraków, Poland
               2023/07
               2021/06
                          EAS 2021, Leiden (Virtual), The Netherlands
               2017/08
                          SMG20, Durham, UK
                          EWASS 2015 - Galaxy studies in the mid-infrared form space and ground, Tenerife, Spain
               2014/06
COLLOQUIA.
SEMINARS, AND TALKS
```

Co-I - NOEMA S22CN (20h A grade): Optically-dark galaxies in the EGS field

Co-I - NOEMA M21AA (159h A grade): NOEMA forming-clusters evolution survey (NICE)

Co-I - VLA 21A-133 (165.5h B grade): A golden reference for ISM studies of distant normal galaxies

Co-I - VLA 22A-400 (60h B grade): High redshift star formation and AGN activity in the JWST CEERS public survey

Co-I – VLA 21B-292 (60h C grade): High redshift star formation and AGN activity in the JWST CEERS public survey Co-I – ALMA 2021.1.00815.S (39.8h C grade): Testing structure formation, quenching and gas accretion models

Colloquia series		Through abstract review:
	2022/03	Hypatia Colloquium 2022, ESO Garching, Germany
Invited talk	KS	Through personal invitation:
	2023/05	Space Science & Astrobiology Division seminars, NASA Ames, California, USA
	2023/05	KIPAC Cosmology seminars, Stanford University, California, USA
	2022/02	Department of Astronomy seminars, Stockholm University, Sweden
	2021/12	Joint ALMA Observatory colloquia, Santiago, Chile
	2021/05	CAB MdM seminars, Centro de Astrobiología, Madrid, Spain
	2021/03	IPARCOS astro-seminars, Universidad Complutense, Madrid, Spain
	2019/11	Journal club seminars, IAP, Paris, France
Visitor talk	S	During a scientific visit:
	2022/11	Cake talks, DAWN, Copenhagen, Denmark
	2017/11	Subaru seminars, Subaru Telescope, Hawaii, USA
	2017/11	Freddie seminars, IfA, Hawaii, USA
	2016/04	Advanced radio astronomy seminars, Cornell University, USA
Local talks	6	As a local scientist:
	2023/06	DAp postdocs seminars, CEA Saclay, France
	2020/05	LCEG DAp seminars, CEA Saclay, France
	2019/05	Interferometry seminar, DARK, Copenhagen, Denmark
	2018/03	Cake talks, DARK, Copenhagen, Denmark
STUDEN <sup>T</sup> SUPERVI		
202	2/10–	Maxime Tarrasse, PhD student, CEA Saclay, France – Co-supervisor
202	1/10—	David Blánquez Sese, PhD student, DAWN - DTU, Copenhagen, Denmark – Co-supervisor
2019	9/10–2022/12	Mengyuan Xiao, PhD student, CEA Saclay/Nanjing University, France/China – Co-supervisor
	2021/01–06	David Blánquez Sese, Master student, DAWN - DTU, Copenhagen, Denmark - Co-supervisor
	2020/01–06	Guillaume Villaret, Master student (M1), CEA Saclay, France – Main supervisor
	2022/04–06	Victor Jaulin, Bachelor student (L3), CEA Saclay, France – Main supervisor
TEACHIN EXPERIE		
Teaching assistant		University of Copenhagen (280h over three courses):
	2018	Danish Summer School in observational astronomy (Master level course)
	2017–2018	Cosmology (3 <sup>rd</sup> year physics bachelor course)
	2016	Niels Bohr Institute Summer School in observational astronomy (Master level course)
PROFESSIONAL SERVICE		
Organizati	ion of	
scientific meetings		
	2023/07	EAS 2023 Symposium – Early assembly of galaxies with JWST spatially resolved spectroscopy and photometry (SOC), Krakow, Poland
	2018/06	COSMOS Team Meeting 2018 (LOC), Copenhagen, Denmark
Reviewer		
	2019–	Referee for ApJ, A&A, and MNRAS
	2022–2023	Evaluation of ESO Period 110, 112 proposals
	2021–2023	Evaluation of ALMA Cycle 8, 9, 10 proposals
Others	2018	Evaluation of a Gemini telescope proposal on behalf of the Canadian Time Allocation Committee
001013	2020–	Organization team member of the astrophysics seminars of the DAp, CEA Saclay, France

2018 Creator, organizer and speaker of the seminar series All you always wanted to know about, aimed at discussing and sharing knowledge about general astronomy topics, DARK, Copenhagen, Denmark

### **OUTREACH**

2019/12 Interview for the podcast Hablando con Científicos of cienciaes.com, Madrid, Spain
 2018/10 Exhibiter at the event Art in Science during the Culture Night 2018, Copenhagen, Denmark As winner of the Mega category in the 2017 contest
 2017/10 Exhibiter at the event Art in Science during the Culture Night 2017, Copenhagen, Denmark
 2013/03 Volunteer at La Uni en la Calle (2<sup>nd</sup> edition), Madrid, Spain
 2012/11 Volunteer at the IX Week of Science, Madrid, Spain

#### REFERENCES

Prof. Sune Toft DAWN - U. Copenhagen, Denmark sune@nbi.ku.dk Dr. David Elbaz CEA Saclay, France david.elbaz@cea.fr Prof. Georgios Magdis DAWN - DTU, Denmark geoma@space.dtu.dk Dr. Emanuele Daddi CEA Saclay, France edaddi@cea.fr Dr. Laure Ciesla LAM, France laure.ciesla@lam.fr Prof. Dominik Riechers University of Cologne, Germany riechers@ph1.uni-koeln.de Prof. Pablo G. Pérez-González CAB. Spain pgperez@cab.inta-csic.es Dr. Mark Dickinson NSF's NOIRLab, USA mark.dickinson@noirlab.edu Dr. Natascha M. Föster Schreiber MPE Garching, Germany forster@mpe.mpg.de